BYR 一代贱侠小春春 自行翻译
是他们吗？
Is that them?
天啊，他们来这做什么？
Jesus Christ.
Are they going to do it right here?
你们之前有过这样的经历吗？
Have you guys
ever been through this before?
没有。
- No.
你们最好别理这事，低头做你的事。
it's best to ignore it.
Keep your head down...go back to work.
去吧。
Go on.
别看。
Don't watch!
提摩太・欣？
Timothy Singh?
我是。
Yes.
我们想要和你谈谈。
I'm afraid we have to speak with you.
埃里克・戴尔？
Eric Dale?
-什么？
-埃里克・戴尔？
- Excuse me?
- Eric Dale?
呃，我不是。
I'm not Eric Dale.
哦，对不起。
Oh. I'm so sorry.
他是我老板，在走廊那边。
He's my boss,
he's down the hall.
- 谢了。
- Thanks.
不好意思，戴尔先生？
- Excuse me? Mr. Dale?
这里。
This way.
好吧。
Okay.
我很抱歉……
I'm obviously sorry ...
我们今天来这里
that we are here today;
可现在是特殊时间，你应该很清楚。
but these are extra ordinary times
as you very well must know.
听着，我负责风险管理部
Look, I run risk management...
我不觉得这个部门应该是裁员开始的地方。
I don't really see,
how that's a natural place to start cutting jobs.
请你明白这里没有私人恩怨。
- We hope you understand
that this is in no way personal.
这层楼的大部分人都被炒了。
The majority of this floor is being let go today.
这文件里有
Ms. Bratberg is now going to
公司提供的详细赔偿方案。
run through the details;
of what the firm is offering.
戴尔先生，公司赔偿你半年工资收入的一半。
Mr. Dale the firm is offering you
six months severance,at half your salary.
你可以保留现在手中的所有期货合同。
You will keep all unvested options
that you currently hold.
直到你的这些合同终止为止。
Health will be extended through that period.
你要在明天4点47分之前作出决定
You have till
tomorrow at... 4:47
接受公司的提议，或者重新选举。
to either take the offer or it will be revoked.
明白吗？
Do you understand?
明白。
- Yes.
不幸的是，由于你工作的有非常高的机密性
Unfortunately Mr. Dale, due to the
highly sensitive nature of your work here;
公司必须要做出相对谨慎的一些行动，也许有些会让你觉得冒犯。
the firm has to take certain precautions
for security purposes that may seem punitive in nature.
我希望，你已经为公司工作了19年
I hope considering your.....
over 19 years of service to the firm,
你应该知道，公司的这些行为
you will understand that these measures
are in no way..
丝毫没有对你的工作或者性格有不满的意思。
a reflection of the firm's feelings
towards your performance or your character.
-我不明白。
-她在向你道歉，
- I don't understand.
- She's apologizing...
为了马上会发生的事情。
for what's about to happen.
你的公司邮箱，浏览器
Your company email,
access to the server,
还有大楼的通行证，你的手机信息和服务
access to the building,
and your mobil data and phone service
在这会议结束后将都会终止。
will all be severed as of this meeting.
这位先生会带你去你的办公室把你的私人物品带走。
And, This gentleman, will take you to your office.
So, you can clear out your personal belongings.
那我现在在做的事情怎么办？
What about the..
what I'm currently working on?
有的事我正做到一半……
-公司已经有了移交计划，也准备好了怎么继续下去
I'm in the middle of something...
- The firm has worked out its transition plan.
and is prepared to move forward,
但是我们还是很感谢你能考虑到这些。
But, we do we appreciate your concern.
我们知道这很难让人接受，这是我的名片
We understand that this is very difficult;
and here is my card.
如果在接下来的几周内，
你对这影响一生的转变有什么困难请联系我。
Please contact me over the next few weeks,
If you'd any assistence with this transition in your life.
真对不起。
I'm sorry.
你没事？
嗯，暂时的。
Are you still alive?
- Uh huh..For now.
不错。
Congratulations.
真是一场血战啊。
-我听说了。
It's a bloodbath.
- I heard.
听着，埃里克
Listen Eric?
如果有什么事我能做我就做了。
If there was something I could have done,
I'd have done it.
好吧，告诉我是谁？
Just tell me...Who was it?
罗杰斯？
-我不会说，你知道的。
Was it Rogers?
- I'm not gonna side, you know me.
罗伯特森？
Robertson?
这个骚逼。我就知道，我去年就该去找她的。
That cunt. I knew it. I never should have
gone to her last year.
埃里克你知道，这只是运气不好。
Look it wasn't anyone. It was bad luck.
And that's all it was.
好吧，好运。
Alright, Well...Good luck.
威尔，我知道这里很多破逼事儿，你最好来看看。
I was just in the middle of alot of shit here
that I think somebody need to take a look at.
埃里克……
Eric Listen...
他们说所有人都要离开这，别碰这里的东西。
They are telling us that everybody needs
to get out of here and just leave this.
我跟感激你能这么想，
但是这不再是你个人的问题了。
And while we appreciate your concern,
but it's not your problem anymore.
祝你好运。
Good luck.
埃里克，我们很抱歉。
Eric, I am very sorry.
- Yeah.
他们要炒了我们吗？
id they say what was going to happen with us?
行了，塞斯。
Jesus Seth.
- What?
这里最近会一直这样
It's gonna get pretty ugly around here for a while..
但你们应该没事。
but you guys will be alright.
我们回头见，好吗？
好。
I'll be seeing you around.
- Alright.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我想对你说声谢谢。
I just wanted to say thanks.
没这个必要。
-有必要有必要。
That's not neccessary.
- Well, it is.
你是这里的负责人……
-我知道。
You were the person around here, that I..
- I know.
这个事情我做了一半，他们不让我继续了。
I was working on something
But they wouldn't let me finish it.
你看看吧。
So, take a look at it.
小心点。
Be careful.
罗伯特森？
Robertson?
塞拉？
Sarah?
你把我手机屏蔽了？
You shut off my phone?
埃里克，我什么都没做。
Eric, I didn't do anything.
操你妈！
Fuck you!
真他妈不容易啊。
It's fucking hedious.
总是要先变糟了才能变好。
It's gonna get worse before it gets better.
来根儿烟？
You got any Nicorettes?
戒了。
I'm out of Nicorettes.
也就是说……
Which means, in about..
过10分钟我要杀人了。（不抽烟）
Ten minutes. I'm gonna kill someone.
你没事吧，山姆？
You alright Sam?
我的狗快死了。
My dog is dying.
对不起。
I'm sorry?
打电话给兽医了，
Just got a phone to the vet,
他妈的在她的肝上长了个瘤。
it's some fucking tumor on her liver.
我每天都要花一千美元让她活着。
I must've paid almost a thousand bucks
a day already, just to keep her alive.
我都不知道还能他妈的做些什么了，威尔。
and I don't have a fucking clue
what to do about it.
他们都……他们都走了。
Well they're all gone.
那……
So?
我们还剩下多少人？
How many do we have left?
大概33个。
About, Thirty-three.
把他们都叫起来，我要跟他们说个事儿。
Make sure everyone is out there,
I gotta say something.
他们都在，都准备好了。
Yeah, I know.
They are ready.
好了，大家听着！
Alright, Let's hear it!
你们留下来是有原因的
You are all still here for a reason...
这层楼80%的人都离开这里了，也不会再回来。
eighty percent of this floor was just sent home...
forever.
我们花了一个小时和他们说再见。
We have spent the last hour saying our good-byes...
他们都是好人，他们都干得不错
they were good people and
they were good at their jobs...
但你们做得更好。
but you all were better.
现在他们走了，这里再也不会有人去考虑他们。
Now they are gone.
They are not to be thought of again.
这是你们的机遇。
This is your opportunity.
这栋楼的所有楼层，从香港到伦敦的所有办公室，
都在发生同样的事
On every floor of this building and in every office
from Hong Kong to London the same thing is happening.
等这些都结束了
By the time we are done..
你和你上级中间
3 of every seven guys;
七分之三的人都会离开。
who were standing
between you and your boss's job...are gone.
这就是你们的机遇。
That is your opportunity.
我在这里工作了34年。
I've been at this place for thirty-four years.
告诉你们，这不会是你们最后一次经历这样的事。
And I can tell you that this will not be
the last time you're gonna go through this.
但你们都是幸存者。
But you all are survivors...
这也就是为什么这家公司在107年之后
And that is how this firm over 107 years,
还越来越壮大。
has continued to grow stronger.
所以，开心点，回去工作，鼓掌吧。
So, keep your heads high... and get back to work.
Let's hear it.
大家都走了，你也走吧。
Everyone is going out man...
you should come on.
我没事。
- Oh, I'm cool. Thanks.
好吧，如果你改主意了，给我打电话。
Okay. Well, if you change your mind,
jut give me a call.
我会的。
I Will.
走吧！
Come!
你们去哪儿？
-大地酒吧。
Where are you guys going?
- The Grand.
我干完了给你打电话。
I'll call you when I'm done.
嘿，为了我们还能留下来，高兴点。
Hey, Be glad, you're still alive.
嗯，没错。
I am.
喂？
Yeah, Hello.
我听不见。
I can't hear you.
你能出去说吗？你那太吵了。
Can you go outside, It's too loud.
你们在哪儿？
-大地酒吧。
Where are you?
- Lugo.
威尔在吗？
威尔・艾默生？
Are you with Will?
- Yeah, Will Emerson?
他应该还在，怎么了？
Yeah, I think he's still here.
好吧我要你和威尔一起回来。
I need you to get Will
and I need you guys to come back up here.
呃，回哪儿？
-办公室。
Uh, Where?
- To the office.
- 什么？
- 说正经的呢。
- What?
- I'm serious.
你要我把咱们老板的老板
You want me to get our boss's boss out of
在周四晚上10点钟从酒吧弄回公司？
a club and bring him back to the office...
at 10:00 on a Thursday night?
咱们老板被解雇了，理论上现在他是咱的老板，
我的确要你这么做。
Our boss just got axed,so technically
he is our boss, and yes that's what I want you to do.
为啥？
Why?
听着哥们儿，相信我，好吗？
我要你们现在回来。
Look man, Just trust me okay.
I need you guys back here, now.
好吧，10分钟。
Alright, we'll be there in ten.
嘿，看看谁在点蜡烛庆祝啊！
Hey, look who it is,
burning the candleat both ends.
为什么你不和我们一起去啊？
Why didn't you come out with us?
又没有其他的裁员计划，又不会让你舔我屁眼儿的。
There aren't anymore cuts planned.
You don't have to kiss my arse.
说真的我都不知道你们要干吗？
I frankly, don't even know,
what it is you guys do.
威尔我很抱歉让你们回办公室。
- 没关系。
Will, I am so sorry I had to bring you guys back..
- That's alright.
埃里克走之前给我这个文件。
Eric gave me this file before he left.
他说他看不出里面是什么
And he told me he couldn't quite figure it out,
在电梯门快关上的时候
他对我说的最后一句话是“小心点”。
And the last thing he says as
the doors on the elevator close is 'be careful'.
他说小心点？
- 对，所以我有点好奇，就打开看了。
He said, Be careful?
- Yeah, So..obviously..I'm little curious.
然后我就意识到，这里的事情……
I get into it a bit and I realize that
the only thing missing..
不是什么好事，威尔。
This is not good, Will.
都打开，这样看着更清楚。
Go to model four, it makes more sense.
这是什么？
What is this?
这基本上是我们帐目里的所有东西。
埃里克在试着算出
This is basically everything that we have in our books.
At any given time. But what Eric was trying to do
这些数据波动的杠杆，不在标准估计亏损风险模型中的可能性。
is to work this numbers for levers of volatility;
that fall outside of our standard VAR model.
什么杠杆？
What are those levers?
这……有点复杂……
简单说。
Well it's a fairly complicated...
- Simplify.
这些杠杆是由历史数据设置
The volatility levers are set using..
然后再按照10%或者15%的分级设置。
historic patterns basically, an then
stretching those patterns out on a 10-15%... roughly.
好吧，然后呢？
- 然后我们开始测试那些证券的走势。
Alright, So?
- So, We are starting to test those historic patterns.
什么时候？
- When?
今天
Today?
周一
Monday...
还有上周五和周三。
- 还有两周之前的周五。
Last friday and wednesday..
- Two Fridays ago.
好吧，我明白了。
Alright, I get it.
我操，这个曲线方向完全反了，这是……
Fuck me. Once this thing gets going in the wrong direction...
他妈的差这么多。
有多大？
It's huge.
- How huge?
损失好像比公司目前的市值还高……
The losses are greater than the current
value of the company...?
还有项目呢，加上项目上的损失，威尔。
Projected...Projected losses...Will.
这还只是我们这层的？
- 没错。
This is just our floor?
- Yes.
埃里克・戴尔在他妈哪儿呢？
- 我不知道，我一直在联系他但是他关机了。
Where the fuck is Eric Dale?
- I don't know. Tried to call him, his phone's off.
什么意思？
- 他们把被裁的人的手机都屏蔽了。
What do you mean?
- They turned off everyone's phone who they axed today.
真他妈傻逼。
Fucking ruthless.
给他家里打电话。
- 在这个点儿？
Call his home.
- At this hour?
对，你确定他是正确的吗？
- 在我看是没什么错了。
Yes... Do we even know if he's right?
- Looks pretty fucking  right to me.
戴尔夫人，我是威尔・艾默生。
Mrs. Dale. This is Will Emerson
我很好，谢谢。能叫下埃里克吗？
I'm fine, thank you.
May I speak with Eric?
找不到，我们试过了，他手机关机了。
你能让他给我打电话吗？
No, we've tried that. His phone appears to be off.
Listen, could you have him call me?
他一回来就让他给我打，他一进门就让他给我打。
The moment he comes in...
the moment he walks through the door.
谢谢你，再见。
Thank you so much.
Goodbye.
- 他他妈的去哪儿了？
- 他好像有三个孩子。 - 所以呢？
- Where the fuck is he?
- Doesn't he have like three kids?  - So?
我不知道，你有三个孩子的话你会不回家吗？
I don't know, would you go home?
我知道他去哪儿了。
I know where he is.
你们俩去接他。
I need you two, to go and get him.
楼下会有车等你们，去吧。
There will be a car waiting for you downstairs.
You need to go.
- 现在？
- 没错，现在。
- Right now?
- Yeah, Right now.
- 你要去干什么？
- 我给山姆打电话。
- What are you going to do?
- I'm gonna call, Sam.
真操蛋。
Fuck me.
- 喂？
- 我威尔。
- Yes?
- It's Will.
现在是夜里11点。
It's 11 O'clock at night?
我知道，我不改这会儿给你打电话……
I know I'm sorry. I wouldn't have called...
你想你该回趟公司。
I think you need to get back here.
现在可是夜里11点！
It's 11 O'clock at night!
我他妈的知道几点！
山姆，你得来看看这个。
I'm well aware of the fucking time!
Sam, I'm telling you..You need to see this.
看什么啊？
See what?
发邮件给我。
Email it to me.
我觉得你还是回来一趟吧。
I don't think that would be a good idea.
好吧我来了。
I'm on my way.
看看这些人。
Look at these people.
在这瞎逛荡，根本不知道要发生什么了。
Wandering around, with absolutely no idea..
what's about to happen.
对么？
- 我试着不去那么想。
Right?
- Well, I try not to let work get to me like that.
你怎么想？
I've noticed that about you.
行了别逗了，我们才23岁。
- 我28了。
Look, we are twenty three years old...
- I'm 28.
我去年赚了差不多25万美元。
I made nearly,
a quarter of a million dollars last year...
卧勒个去，为了什么？
我自己的数据在电脑屏幕上
Fuck! for what...? Pushing some numbers
around on a computer screen,
一帮高傲的傻逼看着这些数据假装什么都懂
so a bunch of glorified crack addicts
could take that  information and pretend to understand it,
然后再拿这些数据去忽悠全世界的穷逼。
and then make a bet against some other
jock half way around the world who if he..
知道吗？我如果不做这个我可能会在赛马场赌7号什么的。
wasn't doing this, he'd be putting number seven
or you know??
最后总是有人赢也有人输。
And at the end of the day one guy win
and the other guy loses.
你知道实际上比这个要复杂得多，对吧？
You do know it's a little more
complicated than that? Right?
没错。
Yeah.
是威尔，问我们有没有找到他呢，怎么说？
It's Will... He wants to know if we've found him?
What do say?
就说……还没找到他呢。
I would say...that
we haven't found him, Yet.
埃里克・戴尔的数据……
Eric Dale...
哦上帝啊……
- 在他由那个傻逼保安看着离开大楼的时候……
Oh Jesus...
- Before he leaves the building, escorted by fucking security...
这跟我没关系。
I had nothing to do with that.
他离开之前把他的一个U盘给了皮特・苏利文
Before he leaves the building
he hands a disk to Peter Sullivan...
谁是皮特・苏利文？
- 别管那么多了，是我们的人。
Who's Peter Sullivan, again?
- Don't matter, One of Eric's guys.
在电梯门关上之前
Before, the elevator doors are closing..
他说的最后一句话是
The last thing he says is...
“小心点”
'Be Careful'
“小心点”？
- 没错。     - 什么意思？
'Be Careful'?
- Yeah.               - Why?
看看这个。
Take a look.
哦天啊，你知道我看不了这个。
直接告诉我吧。
Oh Jesus, You know i can't read this fucking thing!
Speak to me in English.
这个叫皮特・苏利文的小子因为你所说的话的激励，
顺便说一句，你讲的确实不错
Basically, this kid, Peter Sullivan..
He gets all inspired by you pep talk, Nice job! By the way..
开完会之后他埋头苦干，
He dealt straight in, after work.
现在我觉得他找到问题所在了。
- 找到了？
And I think he nailed it.
- Nailed it?
是的，我觉得他找到了埃里克没找出的问题。
Yeah, I think he figured out what Eric was missing.
看上去不怎么样，山姆。
...it isn't good, Sam.
这些是……
These here are the...
股市上历史数据的指标变化，是我们系统分析的主要依据……
historical volatility index limits, which of course,
our entire trading model relies on pretty fuckingheavily...
我们现在做的事很大程度上都依赖这个东西。
但是当这些数据都超过预警限制之后，
And well, we are now so levered up.
But once it gets outside those limits
事情立马就变得很操蛋了。
it gets ugly in a hurry.
我们离预警限制有多近？
And how close to those limits have we gotten?
哦山姆，我们超过了预警……
Oh Sam, we're beyond close...
之前的两周里，我们已经冲破这些预警限制5、6次了
We broke through five or six days over the last two weeks,
Now somehow, we've managed
现在我们又回到了限制区域内，就现在来说……
- 现在？
to stay on the upside  of it... for now...
- For now?
你看，这是接下来如果我们跑到限制之外会发生的事。
Well look.. what happens here
when we get on the wrong side of it.
等一下，我们在看什么？
What am I looking at?
来看这儿的数字。
You're looking at this figure here.
喔……这个是？
- 没错。
Wow...is that?
- Yeah.
尽管这不是历史上我们经历过的最糟糕的情况。
And that wouldn't even be that bad a day
for us... historically speaking.
这个数据对吗？
Is that figure right?
埃里克・戴尔呢？
- 我们把他的手机屏蔽了。
Where is Eric Dale?
- We shut his phone off.
然后我给他老婆打了电话，她说他不在家。
So, I called his wife.
Who says,  he's not home.
他他妈的蹲在哪儿哭呢吧……
He's probably crying in a fucking beer somewhere.
发现这个事儿的小子呢？
- 我让他们出去找埃里克了。
Where's the kid who did this?
- Out looking for Eric.
你觉得他知道自己在干什么吗？
- 让他们回来，赶快！
Do you think he knows what he's doing?
- Get him back.
这些女的一晚上挣多少钱？
1500美元？
2000美元？
2 grand?
好吧，没问题。
Okay,
Yeah.
好吧，那你说罗杰斯一年挣多少钱？
Alright, so come on,
What'a you think Rogers makes in a year?
我不知道……
I have no idea?
猜一个。
Come on, play along.
30多万？
Three quarters of a million?
别逗了。
Come on.
这也太不沾边儿了。
Not even close.
要多得多。
Much more.
100万？
A million?
威尔・艾默生去年挣了250万.
Will Emerson made two and half million last year.
你怎么知道的？
How do you know that?
他告诉我的，我问他了。
He told me.  Well I asked him.
靠谱儿吗？
- 差不多吧。
Do you think that's true?
- Yeah probably.
真操蛋……
- 为毛啊？
That's fucked up.
- Why, why's that fucked up?
你觉得这正常吗？
- 对吧，正常……是吗？
Does that seem right to you?
Right?
上帝啊。
Jesus.
所以你想想罗杰斯挣了多少？
- 我真没这个概念，塞斯。我就知道堵车真他妈烦。
So, what do you think that means Rogers puts away?
- I have no idea, Seth. This traffic's a fucking nightmare.
伙计们？
Gentlemen?
和我们一起来吧。
Come with us, please.
山姆，这是我说的塞斯・布雷格曼和皮特・苏利文。
Sam this is Seth Bregman and this is Peter Sullivan.
我们这是去哪儿？
Where are we going?
我们去看看对你刚才的工作别人有什么意见。
Going to get a second opinion on your work Peter.
山姆你有什么要给我们看的？
So Sam what do you have for us?
他们等会儿就来，这个时候找个人做点什么还真是不容易。
Well... they'll be here in a minute. Finding someone
in the copy room at this hour was a little bit of a challenge.
好吧我们先介绍一下吧。这是塞拉・罗伯特森，
首席风险评估分析师。
Okay, let's go right into introduction. This is Sarah Robertson
who you know, chief risk assessment officer..
拉米什・沙，楼上办公室的，大卫・宏公司内部的咨询师。
Ramesh Shah from upstairs and David Horn
one of the firm's in house council.
很高兴见到你们，这位是我们的交易负责人，威尔・艾默生。
Nice to meet you all.
This is my head of trading, Will Emerson.
皮特・苏利文和塞斯・布雷格曼，都是风险部的。
Peter Sullivan, and Seth Bregman.
They work in our risk department.
埃里克・戴尔呢？
Where is Eric Dale?
他在今天被解雇了。
He was let go today.
那你们风险部还剩下谁？
Who's left in your risk department?
今天在我们这的是皮特
As of today that would be Peter
和我们的初级分析师塞斯。
and our junior analyst Seth...?
威尔・艾默生？
- 发给大家吧。
Will Emerson?
- Please just hand it out.
显然埃里克已经分析了一段时间了，但是没能完成。
Apparently Eric had been working on
this for some time but was unable to finish it,
今天早上他离开公司的时候
This morning, when he left the building;
他把这件事交给皮特让他看看。
He handed the program to Peter here,
and asked him to take a look at it.
皮特看了。
Peter did.
他把埃里克没做的几件事做了。
He put in a few things out that
Eric seemed to be missing..
你看到的这就是结果。
and this is what came out.
皮特这是你做的？
Peter, Is this your work?
大部分是戴尔先生的工作……
Mostly Mr. Dale's...
但是这是你的手稿？
- But is this your draft?
对。
- Yes.
我只是在戴尔先生的基础上进行了展开。
嗯，是我做的。
Again, expanded on original
work of Eric's. But yes.
- 你是什么背景？
- 我的背景？
- What is your background?
- My background?
- 你的简历。
- 我在公司一直和埃里克一起工作，已经两年半了……
Your CV.
-  I've been with the firm for 2 and half years
working with Eric that whole time...
但是我还有MIT的工程师和专业推动力学的博士学位。
But I hold a doctorate in engineering, speciality in propulsion,
from MIT, with a Bachelors from Penn.
专业推动力学是什么？
What's a specialty in propulsion, exactly?
我的论文是关于固定配比现有数据对重力流失方面的研究。
My thesis was a study in the way that friction ratios effect
steering outcomes in aeronautical use under reduced gravity loads.
- 所以你是个火箭科学家？
- 曾经是。
So, you are a rocket scientist?
- I was.
有意思，那你怎么又来了这？
Interesting.
How did you end up here?
反正都是数字么，只是改变一下计算的方式……而且坦白地说，
Well it's all just numbers really, you're just changing
what you're adding up... and if I may speak freely;
这里的收入更吸引人。
the money here is,
considerably more attractive.
现在几点了？
What time is it?
2：15。
It's 2:15.
我想你们两位还没让麦斯知道这事儿？
And I'm guessing, by the fact that
you two haven't said anything that the math checks out?
我们需要时间分析下这个，
Look, we'd need some time to go over this,
苏利文好像很清楚他在做什么。
but Mr. Sullivan here seems to
know what he's doing.
所以看来我们好像有点问题了。
So, it would appear we have a problem.
- 几点了？
- 2：16。
- What time is it?
- 2:16.
操他妈的。
Fuck me.
操。
山姆……
Sam..
把这事儿从我们的帐目上摆平，你的人一般需要多长时间？
How long under normal operations,
would it take your people to clear that from our books?
什么？
What?
- 所有的？
- 没错。
- All of it?
- Yes.
我不知道，几周吧。
I don't know, weeks.
- 几周？
- 没错，几周。
- Weeks?
- Yeah, weeks.
但你很清楚我们的生意是要买和卖。
But as you certainly know
our business is selling AND buying.
没有任何一方都做不成。
Doesn't work for very long without both components.
如果我们现在停止买入一两天，
We suddenly stops buying for a day or two;
这可不是什么能藏得住的事，
that's not something you can
ust doesn't hide under the rug, it gets out
一旦传出去……很快我们就玩儿完。
and when it does...
this whole this thing comes to a end... and  right quick.
- 我明白了。
- 真的？
- I understand.
- Do you?
真的。
Yes.
你和皮特森的楼层上还剩下多少交易员？
How many traders do we have left between
your floor and Petersen's?
- 我不知道，应该是……60个？
- 对，60个。
I don't know, what? Sixty?
- sixty.
我们再仔细看看这个，毕竟这是用估计亏损风险数值算出来的。
Jared as I looke at this more closely,
it's these VAR numbers that are really setting this thing off.
就像我刚才说的，直说的话，
As I was saying..just speaking completely off the record.
用不了多久就会有人发现我们的这些问题。
It's only a matter of time
before someone else startsputting these in.
他们也会算出同样的结果。
and they come up with exactly the same results.
就是我们现在看的这份。
And look at exactly
what we're looking at right now;
如果他们现在还没有看到的话。
If they haven't already.
明白了。
Understood.
萨拉，你允许放在账面上的资产价值是多少？
And Sarah, what value would you allow to be
placed on those assets
如果必须放的话？
that might be left on the books,
if they had to?
为什么还在账面上？
Why would they still be on the books?
- 因为显然没有人愿意去买这些傻逼玩意儿了。
- 你妈逼山姆！你丫让我安静会儿行吗？
- Because suddenly nobody wants to fucking buy them.
- Fuck you Sam! Will you give me a fucking break here?
没有市场的话，这要花上几周甚至几个月的时间
我才能算出精确的数字。
Without an active market, it'd take weeks or months
for me to come up with accurate value on them.
我要一排一排的算。
You'll have to go block by block.
塞斯，你们给我们点时间好吗？
Seth, Could you please,
give us for a few moments.
皮特？
And Peter?
- 还有人知道这个吗？
- 除了我们没别人了。
- Has anyone else has seen this?
- No one aside from us.
- 还有埃里克・戴尔？
- 对。
- And Eric Dale?
- Yes.
而且我们还不知道埃里克・戴尔在哪儿？
And can it really be possible that we don't know,
where Eric Dale is?
我给他老婆打电话了，他还没回家……
而且我们还把他的手机屏蔽了。
I called his wife. He hasn't come home yet
...and we turned off his phone today.
真牛逼。我想知道他去哪儿了。
Perfect. Well, I'd like to know where he is.
我了个擦擦，那家伙是谁啊？
Jesus fucking Christ! Who is that guy?
- 山姆的老板。
- 我以为他应该得有50岁了。
- He's Sam's boss.
- He looks like he's fifteen years old.
- 他才40。
- 怎么会有这种事儿？
- He's Forty.
- Yeah, How does that happen?
这种事儿一直就有。
Oh it happens all the time.
除了我以外。他就是他妈的杀人犯。
Except to me.
He's a fucking killer.
他们在里面会谈些什么呢？
What are they talking about, in there?
不会是什么好事。
It aint pretty.
会是什么不好的？
What aint pretty?
如果大家都不买我们的货了……
If people suddenly stop buying what we're selling....
杰瑞，你不能想做什么就做什么。
Jared, you cannot be doing
what you are thinking about doing?
我没什么别的选择。
Well, I don't see any other choice.
什么意思？你他妈没的选择？
What does that mean?
Fuck you... you don't have a choice.
我有吗？山姆你到底有没有看过这些数字？
Fuck me? Did you even looked at the numbers Sam??
当然，我看过。
Yes, but what do I know.
沙，如果我说错了纠正我一下。
Correct me, if i'm wrong, Mr.Shah.
但是这些数据不再是
These number, they don't add up.
1+1=2这么简单的做加法了。
One and one, no longer makes Two.
如果可以的话，我还需要一些时间……
If I may, I'd like a little more time.
- 我们之前就谈过这个。
- 我们需要点时间才能给你结果。
- We have talked about this.
- We need a little time before to give you our conclusion.
好吧，我们45分钟之后见。
We meet again in 45 minutes.
山姆，你有那份文件吗？
Sam, do you have the file?
你想怎么办？
What are you going to do?
给他打电话？
Are you going to call him?
我已经打了。
I already have.
上帝啊。
Jesus.
哇，太漂亮了。
Wow. It's gorgeous.
这掉下去也要花不少时间。
It's a long way down.
是啊。
Yes, it is.
我靠，别这样。
Don't do that, C'mon.
知道么有人站在这个边缘要掉下去的时候害怕的不是他们会掉下去。
Did you know the fear most people feel
when they stand on the edge like this isn't the fear of falling.
而是怕他们可能会自己就跳下去。
It's the fear that they might jump?
这玩意儿可深了……
Well, that's very deep and depressing, thank you.
我有时候心里有点阴暗。
Yeah, well...I'm a little dark..
Sometimes.
下来吧，威尔，下来吧。
Come down, please.
C'mon...Will?
好吧，去他妈的。
Yeah, Fuck it!
反正不该是今天。
Not today.
看来他们要让我们把这些破玩意儿全卖了。
So it looks like,
they are gonna make us dump this shit.
什么？
What?
等着瞧吧。
You watch.
怎么了？
How?
- 你会知道的。
- 他们怎么能这么干？
- You'll see!
- How could they do that?
是不能，不可能这么干。但是他们会有办法的。
You can't...it's impossible.
But they'll figure out a way.
我在这地方10年了，我见过的事情你们都……
I've been at this place
for ten years and I've seen some things you wouldn't..
你们根本都不会相信。
you wouldn't believe...
这些都搞定的时候，他们根本不会有什么损失。
即使其他所有人都在赔钱，
when all is said and done... they do not lose money.
They don't mind if everyone else does,
但他们不会。
but they don't loose.
威尔？
Will?
你去年真的挣了250万？
Did you really make two and half million last year?
嗯，对。
Yeah..sure.
你怎么花的这钱？
How did you spend it all?
很快就空了。
They expire quickly.
你知道的，口袋里的钱总是很快就没了。
You know, You'll learn and spend
what's in your pocket.
250万美元很快就花完了？
Two and half millions goes quickly?
对，我们算算看。
Alright, let's see.
税收拿走了一半，只给我剩了150万。
The tax man takes half up front.
So, you're left with one and a quarter.
房贷又花了30万。
My morgage takes another 300 grand.
我又给我爸妈50万让他们花。
I send 150 home for my parents,
you know..to keep them going.
- 这多少了？
- 80万。
- So, what's left?
- Eight hundred.
15万买车，
I spend 150 on a car.
7万5花在饭店里，
About 75 in restaurants,
大概，5万买衣服，
Probably, 50 on clothes.
我存了40万以防万一。
And I put 400 away for a rainy day...
聪明。
That's smar.
嗯，看起来金融风暴就要来了。
Yeah, as it turns out.
It looks like the storm's coming.
还有12万5呢？
You still got 125.
我花了76，520美元在找小姐和看脱衣舞上。
但主要是找鸡。
Yeah, I did spent 76,520 dollars on
Hookers, booze and dancers. But mainly, hookers.
7万6500？
76,5..?
一开始我也很震惊，但后来我意识到
我可以以娱乐开销的名义报销一大部分。
Yeah, It was a little shock initially, but then i realise that
I could claim most of it off, as entertainment.
你多大了？
How old are you?
43。
43.
真是怪了。
This is bizzare.
这就像个梦。
It's like a...dream.
我也不知道，好像我们刚睡醒。
Well, I don't know,
seems like we actually may have just woken up.
请进。
Come in.
怎么样？
How do we look?
我该走了。
I should go.
不，你要留下来。
No, you should stay.
怎么？
So?
没有错……
It's legit...
那孩子是对的。
the kid killed it.
这个公式没用了。
The formula is worthless.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
公式失效了。
It's broken.
全世界有8兆美元的钱
There are eight trillion dollars of paper
都指着这个公式呢。
around the world relying on that equation??
但是我们错了。
We were wrong.
不，你的意思是……你错了。
No, You mean..
you were wrong.
别惹我生气……
Don't get me started....
我们谈过这个的！
We discussed this!
我去会议室了。
I'm heading to the conference room.
不，你该听听这个。
No, I want you to hear this.
我不想听。
I don't want to hear this.
你觉得我在这呆那么久干吗？
How do you think
I've stuck around this place so long?
我给图尔德打电话了。
I've called Tuld.
我们有备用方案吗？
Is there a contingency plan here?
备用方案？
A contingency plan?
- 是的。
- 没有，我们把所有的都押在这上面了。
- Yes.
- No, We went all in on this one.
那我们现在彻底没辙了，是么？
So, we've got ourselves quite exposed
here... haven't we?
拿图尔德没辙了还是拿市场没辙？
To Tuld or the market?
都是。
To both.
他来了？
He's here?
图尔德的直升机到了。
Tuld's helicopter just landed.
我知道，一起来吧。
I know, come with us.
- 山姆呢？
- 我不知道，我们几个都要去吗？        - 是的。
- Where's Sam?
- I don't know, You sure..you want all of us?       -Yes.
进去之前给大家一点建议。
Just one piece of advice
for everyone before we go in there.
一会场面可能会不太好看，
This could get a little ugly.
但不管怎么样……实话实说就好了。
不要拍马屁，刚才怎么说的一会儿就还怎么说。
but whatever you do... just... tell the truth.
No sugar coating. Do not change a word of it.
谁都别在这自作聪明。
no one here is smart enough...
那个火箭科学家也是。
Including the rocket scientist.
这边。
This way please.
他已经在里面等你了。
He's already in there waiting for you.
很好。
Excellent!
大家坐吧。
Please sit down.
欢迎大家。
Welcome everyone.
很抱歉在这么晚了叫大家过来，
I must apologize for dragging you all
here at such an uncommon hour;
但据我所知，有些事情要马上处理！
but from what I've been told,
this matter needs to be handled urgently!
事实上，我们几周前就应该处理了。
so urgently, in fact.. it probably should
have been addressed weeks ago...
可我们现在居然还在分析！
but that is spilled milk...
Under the bridge!
那么，谁和我说说到底发生了什么？
So, why doesn't somebody tell me
what they think is going on here?
图尔德先生，就像我之前说的，
Well, Mr. Tuld..
as I mentioned earlier..
如果你把第13页最上面的数字和……
if you compare the figure at the top page 13...
杰瑞，你就直说吧。
Jared, it's a ?..just speak to me in plain english.
我要听那个把这个算出来的人说……苏利文，对吗？
But I'd  like to speak to the guy who put this
together... Mr. Sullivan is it?
他能直接说明白吧？
Does he speak English?
什么？
Sir?
我要和那个算出这些麻烦的分析师说话。
I'd like to speak to the analyst who
seems to have stumbled across this mess.
没问题，是皮特・苏利文，就在那。
Certainly, that would be Peter Sullivan.
Right here.
哦你就是苏利文啊，早上好。
Oh Mr.Sullivan. You are here!
Good morning.
也许你能告诉我这里发生了什么。
And maybe, you could tell me..
what you think is going on here.
而且请你像对孩子说话一样那么解释清楚，
And please speak as you might
to a young child ..
甚至像对一只金毛猎犬说话一样。
or a golden retriever.
这么说吧，不是我的智慧把我带到这个位置上的。
It wasn't brains, that got me here.
I can assure you of that.
好吧，也许您知道我在这和罗杰斯先生一起工作。
Well, sir. As you may or may not
know I work for Mr.Rogers.
是一位风险评估管理分析师。
As an associate in the risk assessment
and management office at GSMBS
放松点，站起来说，大点声
Just relax, stand up.
Tell us in clear voice.
告诉大家问题在哪。
What is the nature of the problem.
好的……您应该知道，在过去的36到40个月里，
Yes... Well as you probably know over the
last 36-40 months the firm has begun
公司在包装新的按揭证券理财产品，
packaging new MBS products;
它是包含交易国债等好几块的产品组合。
that combine several different traunches of rating
classification in one tradable security.
这个产品带来了很大利润，我想这个您知道的。
This has been enourmously profitable...
as I imagine you noticed.
我知道。
I have.
现在公司的这个产品每天都能卖出很多。
Well the firm is currently doing
a considerable amount of this business every day.
我们今天在这的主要问题是……
The problem..which is I guess
why we are here tonight.
我们花了……公司花了大概一个月的时间……
is that it takes us...
the firm, about a month...
才做好产品的风险分析。
to layer these products correctly.
这从风险控制管理的角度上来说是个难题。
thereby posing a challenge
from a risk assessment standpoint.
不好意思，什么难题？
And Mr. Sullivan that challenge is?
我们要花上比想象多得多的时间来做这件事。
We have to hold these assets on our books
longer than we might ideally like to.
好吧。
Yes.
但问题是，这些只是抵押债款，所以由于杠杆效应，
But the key factor is here is, these are essentially just mortgages,
that has allowed us to push the leverage considerably..
让我们做了原本我们做不到或者不愿意做的一些事情，
beyond what you might be willing or allowed to do;
在任何情况下，我们可能把风险一再调高但是却没有预警。
in any other circumstance, thereby
pushing the risk profile without raising any red flags.
好，谢谢，请坐。我猜你这报告说的是，
Now, Thank you...sit down.
What I am guessing, your report here says;
给我点时间，
give me some rope,
我想你的意思是……
what I am guessing, it says is that..
是不是说
considering the, shall we say?
尽管过去一两周我们一路颠簸。
bumpy road, we've been on the last week or so.
但你和你同事辛苦工作的结果……
But the figures your brilliant co- workers up
the line ahead of you had come up with..
没什么用。
don't make much sense anymore;
根据我们今天看到的局面。
Considering what's taking place today?
实际上不是今天才发生的，
Actually not taking place today...
这个情况两周前就开始了。
but what's already taken place
over the last two weeks.
那么你是说，这早就发生了？
So, you are saying , this had already happened?
是吧。
Sort of.
苏利文，你的计算模型说明了什么问题？
And Mr. Sullivan,
what does your model say that that means...for us here?
我们得出了一个推测。
Well, that's where it becomes a projection.
但是……呃……
But... ummm..
你在和我说，苏利文先生。
You're speaking with me Mr. Sullivan.
好吧……
Well... sir...
如果我们账面上的这些资产下跌下跌25%的话，
If those assets decrease..by just 25 percent,
and remain on our books...
那损失……
that loss...
可能比我们整个公司现在的市值还要多。
would be greater than the current market
capitalization of this entire company.
你的意思……
So what you're telling me...
就是说……
is that...
音乐要停了。
music is about to stop.
而我们手里堆积了整个资产阶级的
and we are going to be left holding...
'the biggest bag of odorous excrement'
所有的破烂玩意儿？
ever assembled in the history of capitalism?
呃先生，我可能……
Well sir, I'm not sure I'd..
不太会这么去形容这件事，但是让我用你的话来说的话，
put it that way, but let me clarify...using your analogy,
这个模型显示出……
what this model shows...
你说的音乐，只是越来越慢了，
is the music, so to speak,
just slowing,
如果像你说的音乐要停了，
If the music were to stop,
as you put it,
这个模型还不是，
then this model would not be even close;
其实这比音乐停了要更糟糕。
to that scenario.
It would be considerably worse.
我跟你说，苏利文。
Let me tell you something Mr. Sullivan.
你想没想过为什么我会坐在这个位子上？
Do you care to know,
why I'm in this chair with you all?
为什么我是你们的老板？
Why I earn the big bucks?
想过。
Yes.
我坐上这个位置只有一个原因，
I'm here for one reason
也就一个原因。
and one reason alone.
我在这里去猜，那音乐一周、一个月、
I'm here to guess,
what the music might do, a week, a month,
甚至一年之后会是什么样。
a year from now.
这就是原因！
That's it!
没别的了。
nothing more...
我今天晚上站在这……
I'm standing here tonight...
我觉得我什么音・乐・都・没・听・到……
I'm afraid that,
I don't hear... a... thing...
万籁俱寂。
just... silence!
现在我们知道音乐停了，我们该怎么办？
So, now that we know that the music has
stopped, what can we do about it?
科恩，罗伯特森
Mr. Cohen,
Ms. Robertson,
我想这是你们该表现的时候了。
I'm afraid, I think..this is where
you are supposed to step back in.
我们今晚一直都在依靠苏利文先生。
Lord knows we've relied enough
on Mr. Sullivan tonight.
你有什么要给我们看的？
What have you got for us?
你们第一天走进我办公室的时候
What have I told you since...
我对你们说了什么？
the first day you walked into my office?
这个行业里有三种生存模式：
There are three ways
to make a living in this business...
更快，更聪明，或者更能忽悠。
Be first, be smarter,
or cheat.
我不骗人。
Now, I don't cheat...
尽管我认为我们这里有很多聪明人，
And although I like to think,
we've some pretty smart people in this building.
但我想去做到更快会简单的多。
it sure is a hell of a lot easier
to just be first.
今天把这些全都卖了。
Sell it all...today!
能做到么，山姆？
Is that even possible Sam?
可以，但是成本呢？
Yes, but at what cost?
那是必须付出的。
I'll have to pay.
真的么？
Really?
我这么觉得。
I think so.
这些东西会以什么方式再回到我们手中？
Where does this gonna come back to us?
各种方式。
Everywhere.
山姆，我觉得你好像没听懂你的人刚才说的话……
Sam, I don't think you seem to understand
what your boy here had just said...
如果我让你处理，
if I made you...
你会怎么做？
how would you do it?
让交易员在早上6点半开例会，
Well, you call the traders in
for their normal 6:30 meeting...
老实告诉他们情况。
and you be honest with them.
反正他们很快都会知道。
B'cos they're gonna know it's the end either way.
所以你要给他们一份奖励，很多的奖金。
so you'd have to throw them a bone,
and a pretty big one.
然后你要赶紧出来，风暴来临了……
And then, you've gotta come
out of the gate storming...
不要掉期交易，什么都不要。
No swaps..no nothing.
10：15之前干掉40%，11点要卖完所有的东西。
因为中午的时候，
40 percent done by 10:15; by 11 O'clock
all your trades have to be gone. 'cos by lunch-time
消息就会传出去了。
words are gonna be out.
拖到2点的话还能以65%的成本价卖出就已经算是你走运了。
and by two o'clock you'll be getting 65 cents
on the dollar, if you're lucky,
而且联邦调查局的人马上就会过来找你麻烦。
and the feds will be in here up your ass;
trying to slow us down.
- 拉米什？
- 他们会让你慢下来……
- Ramesh?
- They can slow you down...
但不会阻止你，这是你自己的买卖。
but they can't stop you.
it's yours to sell.
约翰……就算……
John...even if..
我们能把问题摆平……
we manage pull that off,
and that's saying something...
但真正的问题是……
The real question is...
我们卖给谁？
Who are we selling this to?
过去两年里的那些买家，以及其他任何愿意买的人。
The same people we've been selling to
for the last two years, and whoever else will buy it.
但是，如果你这么做了。
But John, If you do this.
你会让市场瘫痪好几年，那就完蛋了。
You would've killed that market
for years. It's over.
而且你知道你卖的东西毫无价值。
And you are selling something
that you know has no value.
我们以市场的价格
We are selling to willing buyers
卖给愿意购买的买家
at a current fair market price,
然后我们就能活下来！
so that WE may survive!
但以后你再也不能向那些人卖出任何东西了。
You'll never sell anything to any of
those people ever again.
- 我知道。
- 你知道？
- I understand.
- Do you?
- 你知道什么？！
- Do You???
就这么定了！
This is it!
我告诉你，这就是命令！
I'm telling you.
This is it.
现在是……凌晨4点钟。
It's 4:00...O'clock.
杰瑞你在5点之前给我个方案。
Jared you've got till 5:00 to break this down
and draw me up a plan.
除了这的人还有谁知道这件事的？哪怕一点也算？
Is there anyone else who knows
what's in there right now, block by block?
埃里克・戴尔。
Eric Dale.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
他今天已经被公司解雇了。
As of today he is no longer with the firm.
我们一直在找他。
We have been trying to locate him.
- 卡梅隆？      - 说。
- 六点之前给我把埃里克・戴尔带过来。
- Carmelo?      - Yes?
- Get me Eric Dale here by Six.
知道了。
Done.
我们一小时之后再回来开会。
We meet back here in an hour.
山姆，我们谈谈。
Sam, let's talk.
这就是这座城市里最黑暗的地方。
This is a hell of a town.
我一直都很喜欢这地方。
I've always loved this place.
从我来这儿的第一天开始，喜欢这里的一切。
Since the day i arived.
Everything about it.
山姆，这件事上你会和我站在一起么？
Sam, are you gonna go with me on this?
我不知道，约翰。
I don't know John.
这事儿太糟糕了。
This one is very ugly.
咱们都曾经是销售人员。
You and I were salesmen.
我们卖东西，这就是我们做的，一点都不复杂。
We sell. That's what we do.
It's not complicated.
没错。
Exactly.
而且你很他妈的清楚
And you know damn well..
你不会卖任何没价值没回报的东西。
you don't make a sale unless
you think the guy is gonna come back for more,
这是我们的教训，而且明天我们就完蛋了。
That's the lesson we learned.
and tomorrow we are done.
这次搞大了。
This is the big one.
我们中的大部分人都逃不出这次灾难。
Most of us aren't gonna make it out of this one.
- 我们？
- 整个华尔街。
- Us?
- The street.
你什么意思？
What are you talking about?
这周发生的事不是我要面对的最终局面。
This isn't  the last 'situation' I will
have to deal with this week.
这还只是个开始。
This is just the start.
这个开始是因为你开始了这一切。
It's the start because you are starting it.
也许吧，但我不相信。
Maybe. But I don't believe that.
反正不是这次。
Not this time.
那些数字都没法加了。
The numbers just don't add up anymore.
我同意你这个观点。这话我很多年前就说过了。
Well I agree with you there.
I've been saying that for years.
如果外面的孩子算出来的这结果……
I mean if this kid out there can
come up with this thing...?
我没办法明知道结果还要去害其他人。
I don't think I can go in knowing what I
know and put the hammer down on these guys like this.
山姆你什么时候变成这么个软蛋了？
When did you start becoming so soft, Sam?
你他妈才软蛋，是你自己害怕了。
Fuck you soft, you're panicking.
如果你第一个走出这个门，
If you're the first one out the door;
那就不叫害怕。
That's not called panicking.
显然你比我掌握了更多信息。
Well, you are obviously operating
with more information than i have.
但我想这些足够毁了这公司了。
But I think this could destroy this firm.
没人会在相信你了。
No one will ever trust you again.
你在知情的情况下把人家的生意毁掉。彻底的。
Knowingly putting people out of business.
Full stop.
然我来处理吧，山姆。
Let me deal with that, Sam.
怎么样？
How'd that go?
都他妈的傻逼。
This is a fucking shit show.
- 他们真打算这么干了？
- 大概吧。
- They are gonna go with it?
- Probably.
不勒个是吧！
Jesus!
记住今天吧，孩子们
Remember this day boys,
记着今天。
Remember this day.
我们现在什么策略？
What's the strategy here?
这正是我要下楼和他们一起研究的事情。
Well, that's why i'm headed downstairs,
to work it with my guys.
不，是你、我还有约翰。
No, no, you and I...
With John.
我觉得我们不需要这样，萨拉，我不是这么做事的。
I'm not sure that we need one, Sarah.
That's not the way I do things.
别装逼了。
Please.
听着，他知道我们在做什么，
Listen, He knows where we are still on this.
一直都知道。
All along.
那正是我的意思。
That's exactly my point.
就算知道我们在干什么……
And knowing what was discussed..
我也觉得不会有人来帮你。
by both you and I. I don't think
this could provide you with anything.
也不会有人假装安慰你。
other than, false sense of comfort.
我不是在求安慰。
I'm not looking for sense of comfort.
估计也求不到。
I don't think there's one to be found.
那么再问一遍，现在有什么对策？
So again, what's the strategy?
我想我们也做不了什么。
I'm just not sure there's much more to do in this.
这事已经很清楚了，
It's very simple.
别想瞒着我。
Don't even think of fucking me on this.
因为如果我歇菜了，
because if we are going down...
你也好不了。
you damn well know we'll  be together.
不，我不这么觉得。
No, I'm not sure I do know that.
你觉得图尔德去年挣了多少钱？
What do you think Tuld made last year?
你他妈的能闭嘴么？
Would you shut the fuck up.
8千6百万。
86 mil.
包括工资和分红。
In bonuses and salary .
真的？
Really?
当然，有公开记录的。
Sure, it's public record.
他曾经有十多亿美元呢。
He was worth a billion.
曾经？
Was?
直到今天，以后就不是了。
Until today.
我需要点新鲜空气。
I could use some real air.
好主意。
Probably a good idea.
您好，我是威尔・艾默生。
Hello, Will Emerson.
喂？
Hello?
不用了谢谢，我知道了。
No, thank you. I understand.
不，我们会小心的。
No, we'll be discreet.
怎么了？
What?
埃里克老婆。
Eric's wife.
他没事，在家呢，就是不想和我们说话。
也不知道他老婆给我打电话。
He's alive, he's home. He doesn't wanna
speak to us. He doesn't know she rang me.
他住哪儿？
Where's he live?
住海兹。
The heights.
我们要叫图尔德手下那个人吗？
Should we call Tuld's guy?
不，这是埃里克。叫那些人去是我们最不得已的办法。
你们俩去把他找回来。
No.it's Eric...the last thing we need is those guys
going over there, you two go try to get him.
但是记得要赶在6点之前。
But you've got to be back here by 6:00 AM.
我讨厌布鲁克林。
I hate Brooklyn.
我能进来么？
May I come in?
坐吧。
Please, sit down.
嗯，我们准备……
So... we are going to do this thing.
嗯。
Okay.
可能会很紧张。
It's going to be tight.
山姆会和我们一起吗？
Is Sam on board?
现在还没有。
Not yet.
萨拉，
Sarah,
我需要一个负责人……
I need a head.
对交易员们负责任。
to feed to the traders...
on the floor and the board.
是我还是科恩？
Is it me or Cohen?
就是你。
It's you.
你应该知道……
Of course you are...
我之前就提醒过你和科恩这件事。
well aware I filtered several warnings
to you and Cohen about this .
一年前就说过。
A year ago.
我真不觉得现在该说这个。
I really don't think that's the best path for you
to be taking at this point.
你会得到很好的补偿的。
you're going to be well taken care of.
显然这有点复杂。
Obviously it's quite complicated.
约翰，我了解相关的条款……
John I was told that in no uncertain terms...
这一直是个灰色区域。
It was always a very grey area.
其实那个时候我和你们
Actually it was made very clear at the time,
就把这事说的很清楚了。
by you and I and Cohen.
我希望你不要再跟我扯这个事儿了。
I'd really appreciate it that you didn't fight me on this...
这事我们全都搞砸了。
We all fucked this one up pretty good...
我要你在这呆到股市收盘。
We need you to stay here till
this is finished and the markets close.
我明白。
I understand.
他们一会在楼下和你分析那些数据，
They'll go over the numbers with you downstairs...
祝你好运。
Good luck.
不知道那家伙想干吗？
What's the boy wonder want?
有时间吗？
You got a minute?
- 我们要去接埃里克。
- 我知道，就一会儿。
- We're just off to pick up Eric.
- Yeah I know. Will only take a second.
好吧，怎么了？
Alright, what is it?
我和图尔德担心在这件事上山姆可能会站错位置。
Tuld and I have  concerns that Sam,
may not be step up and do the right thing.
这事儿原来没有过？
It's never been a problem?
没有。
No, it hasn't.
但像现在这样的敏感时期……
But, sometimes in an acute situation,
Such as this...
对于究竟什么是对的
often what is right.
可能招来很多猜忌。
Can take on,
mutiple interpretations.
山姆知道该怎么做。
Sam will step up.
我知道他会的。
Oh, I know..he will.
但是如果他不肯，我是说如果……
But if he doesn't.
IF he does not...
我们要知道你会的。
We need to know that,
You will.
你们要知道我会怎么样？
You need to know that,
I will... What?
你会和我们站在一起。
That you will step up.
我相信，山姆会做出正确的选择。
I have not doubt.
That Sam will make the right decision.
但我想先说清楚，
But, just to make it clear.
他和我对什么是正确的事情，意见很一致。
He and I always have the same interpretation,
Of what's right.
不管是不是什么敏感时期。
No matter, How acute...
the situation.
天啊，这房子真不错。
Jesus, that's a nice place.
没错，他刚买的。
Yeah,  it is.. he just bought it.
希望他用的是现金。
I hope it was with cash.
滚蛋，你个没良心的就不会说点好的，
Fuck me. You are a heartless
little shit sometimes.
不是用的现金。
and it wasn't.
什么都别动！
Don't touch any of the buttons!
你来这干吗？
What are you doing here?
嘿？
Hey?
皮特把你在算模型做完了。
So..Peter finished that model
you were working on.
真的？
Really?
惹了大麻烦了。
Caused a shit storm.
我就知道。
I bet...it did.
你认为他算得对吗？
Do you think he's right?
我知道他是对的。
I know...he's right.
昨天晚上杰瑞・科恩和高级合作伙伴开了一个紧急会议。
Jared Cohen called an emergency meeting
of the senior partners last night.
基于你的那些发现……
Based on your findings..
他们决定把我们手里有的全卖了。
They've decided to liquidate our entire position.
就今天！
Today!
我很抱歉。
I am very sorry about that.
他们担心你一个人在外面，要我把你带回去。
They are worried about you being out here.
And  they want me to get you back.
- 别逗了！
- 他们说的。             - 让他们去死吧。
- Jesus!
- I'm just saying..             - Fuck that.
- 好好考虑一下。
- 得了吧，我签了字，我已经不管这事儿了。
- Don't be rash.
- Forget it, I've signed my papers. I'm out!
他们会给你钱的。
They will pay you.
我已经拿了很多钱了。
I've been paid enough, already.
你知道我原来是造桥的么？
Did you know I built a bridge once?
什么？
Sorry?
造大桥。
A bridge.
我没听说过这事儿。
No, I didn't know that.
我当时是个工程师。
I was an engineer by trade.
那桥从俄亥俄州的多士巴到西维吉尼亚州的玛瑟夫。
It went from Dilles Bottom,
Ohio to Moundsville West Virgina.
距俄亥俄河上方218英尺。
It spans 912 feet above the Ohio river.
每天有1万2千1百人通过这座桥。
12,100 people a day use this thing a day.
算上在惠灵和新马顿赛两头
And It cut out 35 miles...
通过这座桥的总路程有35英里。
of extra driving each way,
between Wheeling and New Martinsville.
加起来的话……
That's a combined...
汽车每天在这座桥上行驶84万7千英里
847,000 miles of driving,a day...
或者每个月2千5百4十1万英里
Worth 25,410,000 miles...a month;
每年3亿4千9百2十万英里
and 304 millions 920,000 miles a year.
这座桥节省了这么多路程。
Saved.
我能在1986年做这样的工程，那是22年前了。
Now, I completed that project in 1986...
that's 22 years ago.
那座桥的寿命大概还可以在上面行驶
60亿7千零8十万2千4百英里的路。
So, Over the life of that one bridge..that's 6 billion...
708 million...240 thousand miles...that haven't had to be driven!
我们算每小时50英里好了。
At what? let's say... 50 miles an hour
那就是1亿3千4百1十6万4千8百个小时。
So, that's a 134 million, 164 thousand
800 hours...
或者说
or
5十5万9千零2十天。
559 thousand 20 days...
所以就那一座桥就省下了当地两个社区里的居民
总共1531年的生命
so that one little bridge has saved the people
of those two communities a combined, 1531 years of their lives
而不至于把那些时间浪费在车里。
not wasted in a fucking car...
1千5百3十1年！
One thousand five hundred and 31 years!
天啊。
Jesus.
我觉得……你该回去了。
I guess... you better get back over there.
好吧。
Yeah.
谢谢你能来。
Thanks for coming by.
没事。
You're welcome.
那他妈的是谁？
Who the fuck is this?
大概，公司的人吧。
I'd imagine, it's the firm's people.
啊？
What?
图尔德不像在你这里失去控制。
Tuld doesn't want any loose ends.
是他炒的我。
He fired me.
真他妈的有病。
Fuck em... Fuck em.
我同意，都是一帮傻逼。所以，回来吧。
I totally agree...Fuck them.
So, come back...
拿着你的钱，5点前你就回家了。
take the money,
You'll be home by five.
否则的话，他们会把你的什么都吞了，红包、期货……
Otherwise, they are going to fight you on everything,
they are going to fight you on the package, the options...
识时务点吧。
Be smart.
好吧，你比我牛逼。
Well..You're a better man than I.
我一直比你牛逼。
That's always been true.
对，对对。
Yes, it has.
这房子不错。
The house looks good.
谢谢。
Thanks.
埃里克……
Hey Eric...
别老这么怪罪自己好吗？
don't beat yourself up too much
about this stuff, alright?
有的人就喜欢开半天车才能回到家。
Some people like driving the long way home.
谁他妈知道呢，对吧？
Who the fuck knows. Right?
啊，你在这。
There he is.
约翰。
John.
怎么样了？
How's it looking?
科恩做的不错，可以照他说的干。
Cohen has done a nice job. It can work.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
就是说，你知道的，
It means, as you very well know,
你是这里很重要的一员。
that you are a very important piece of this puzzle.
这可不是白给的。
It's not a gift.
我要知道这件事上你和我在同一战线。
I need to know you are with me on this.
我和公司站在一起。
I'm with the firm John.
除非你的人相信你，否则我从这些人那什么都得不到……
I won't get what I need out of your boys
on the floor, unless they believe you...
他们得完全信任你才行。
unless they believe in you completely.
帮我一把，行么？
Are you in, on this?
我说过了我持保留意见。
I told you my reservations.
你不能有任何保留！
You can't have reservations!
我现在就要知道！
And I need to know now.
听着，约翰。我一直都是为公司考虑的。让我过去。
Look John..I'm  completely with the firm, as I
always have been. Excuse me.
好吧，威尔，我会被炒吗？
Alright, Will. Am I getting fired?
我不知道。
I don't know.
会的吧，基本上肯定会。
Yeah, almost definitely.
- 那你呢？
- 我不会。
- Are you?
- No.
塞斯，这不是因为你做错了什么。
只是你在错误的时间，加入了错误的公司。
Seth, its nothing you did.
You're just in a wrong firm, in a wrong time.
年轻人总是被裁员的那个。
我没什么好劝你的。
Young guys are always the one to get called.
Listen, nothing i can say'll make you better
你会难受一阵子，过些日子就好了。
It's gonna suck for a while...
and then you'll be fine.
你还好吧？
You alright?
嗯，我没事。
Yeah, yeah. I'm fine.
就现在来说，我很抱歉发生这样的事情。
For what its worth,
I'm sorry this is happening to you.
不用，你没必要这么说。
Don't be. You didn't do it to me.
总之，起码你走的时候会拿到一大笔钱。
Still, at least you're gonna
have some nice cash to walk away with.
也许吧。
I guess.
- 这种事真的会影响到别人的。
- 没错，像我这样的。
- This is really gonna effect people.
- Yeah, it's gonna affect people like me.
不是，我是说其他人。
No, real people.
行了吧，塞斯。
Jesus, Seth.
如果你真的想在这个行当做下去，
你必须相信你自己很重要。而且你就是不错。
If you really wanna do this with your life.
You have to believe you're necessary. And you are.
大家想要这样的生活，香车、豪宅，可是他们根本都付不起。
People wanna live like this. In their cars
and their big fucking houses, that they can't even pay for.
这时候你就非常重要了。
Then, you're necessary.
他们能活得像个国王的唯一理由是
The only reason, that they all get
continue living like kings is
我们用手指把天平往他们那边压了一下。
'cos we got our fingers on the scales in their favour.
我把手拿走了。
I take my hand off.
然后世界才是他妈的真正公平的，但是很快他们就说不要这样。
Well then the whole world gets really fucking fair,
really fucking quickly and nobody asks you one shite.
他们想要我们给他们更多的东西。
They want what we've to give them..
但同时又想假装无辜假装不知道这些东西怎么来的。
but they also wanna you know, play innocent
and pretend they've no idea where it came from.
那就要我来为他们的这些行为埋单，操。
That's more hypocracy than I'm willing to swallow.
So, fuck them.
都他妈傻逼！
Fuck normal people!
你知道么，有趣的是，明天如果这事儿曝光了。
You know, the funny thing is.
Tommorow, if all of these goes tits up.
他们会把我们钉上十字架，极其野蛮。
They're gonna crucify us.
For being, too reckless.
但如果我们错了，
But if we are wrong??
一切又都回到原来那样。
And everything gets back on track.
同样这帮人会开心到尿裤子。
Well then, the same people
are gonna laugh until they piss their pants.
因为我们看起来像穿过那扇门最大的傻逼。
Because, we are gonna look like the biggest
pussies that God ever let through the door.
你觉得我们会错么？
Do you think we are gonna be wrong?
我不知道，别问我。
Nah, i don't know..fuck.
早上好。
Good morning.
皮特……
Peter...
续一根儿？
you want one?
我不抽烟。
I don't smoke.
真好，我也不怎么抽的。
That's good. I don't much either.
累吗？
Are you tired?
累什么？
Of what?
我又没像你那么拼命的工作。
Remember, I don't work as hard as you do.
不是吧。
Oh, That's not true.
就是，我没有。
No it is...actually.
- 我们今天会被解雇吗？
- 也许吧。
- Are we all getting fired after today?
- Probably.
他们会炒了你？
Are they going to fire you?
他们会换种说法。
Well, they won't exactly call it that.
算作怜悯的辞退吧。你不用陪我在这站着。
but... it'll be a mercy killing really.
You don't have to stand out here for me.
我知道，我只是现在还不想回去。
No, I know. I really
don't want to go back in there just yet.
我理解。
I understand that.
我应该认识你儿子。
I think I know your son.
真的？
Really?
不是很熟……但是看起来是个好人。
Not well... but, he always seemed
like a nice person.
他是个好人。
He is a nice person.
还是骂别人坏的词比较多。
I guess you could say a lot worse about a guy.
他知道会发生什么吗？
Does he know what's about to happen?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
你跟他说过吗？
Did you talk to him?
没有，我从没想过要跟他说这个。
No..I hadn't even thought of it.
他们来了。
They're all coming in now.
是啊都来了。
Yes they are.
你以前做过这样的事吗？
Have you ever done anything like this?
从来没有，一点都没有。
No... never.... not even close.
你确定我们只能这么……
Are you sure..it's the only...
这么做对吗？
or the... right thing to do?
对谁来说？
For who?
我不知道。
I'm not sure.
我也不知道。
Neither am I.
你没事吧？
You alright?
你要解雇我。
You are about to fire me.
知道么，我很喜欢在这里工作。
You know, this is..
This is all I've ever wanted to do.
真的？
Really?
你也是吧，嗯？
You as well, huh?
对。
Yes.
真行。
Jesus!
抱歉。
Sorry.
谢谢。
Thank you.
我想他们不光是让你回来。
I didn't think they were going
to be able to get you back here.
他们说接下来2年都要我和他们一起……
They told me they were going to drag me
through hell on everything
我的期货、医疗保险……
the next two years..
my options, my healthcare
或者我可以回来挣……
or I could come back here and make...
每个小时17万6千471美元
$176,471.00 an hour
就是在这静静坐着。
to sit quietly...  in this room.
好像也没什么别的选择。
I couldn't see much of choice.
从来就没得选。
It never is.
回过头来看，
Obviously looking back,
之前我们没有足够的紧迫感……
It was expressed with insufficient urgency...
但是你的观点现在大家都知道了。
but your point was passed on...
我希望你知道这点。
I need you to know that.
埃里克。
Eric.
没事，我理解，相信我。
Its okay, I understand,
believe me.
你也做不了什么。
there was nothing you could have done.
我觉得也是……
I guess...
那个时候……好像也没什么选择。
at the time... it didn't seem like
there was much of a choice.
从来没有过。
It never does.
你的信封会是什么样的？
What is your package going to be like?
我不知道，我正等着呢。
I don't know,
that's what I'm waiting for now.
可能会不错。
It probably pretty good.
最好是。
It better be.
非常感谢大家能来这么早。
Thank you all for coming in
a little early this morning,
我知道昨天很糟糕，我希望今天能跟大家说情况有所好转，
I know yesterday was pretty bad,
and I wish I could say that today is going to be less so,
但其实并不是。
but that isn't going to be the case.
现在我应该给你们读这份通知，
Now, I am supposed to read this
statement here to you all here,
但你们有空了自己看吧，我只想告诉你们这发生了什么。
but how bout you read it on your own time
and I'll just tell you what the fuck's going on here.
我昨天整宿都在这。
I've been here all night.
和董事会的人开会讨论。
meeting with the executive committee.
最终决定卖出公司几个关键财产类的所有东西。
and the decision has been made to unwind a considerable
portion of the firm's holdings in several key asset classes.
问题是，在公司看来，
The crux of it is... in the firm's thinking.
派对在今天早上结束了。
the party is over as of this morning.
在未来一段时间里，市场会有很大动荡。
There is going to be considerable turmoil
in the markets for the foreseeable future.
他们觉得，这个动荡最好从我们这里开始。
And they believe...
it is better, that this turmoil begin with us...
结果就是……
as a result...
公司决定卖出
the firm has decided to liquidate
大部分的固定收入的按揭证券
its majority positions of fixed income MBS..
今天一天。
today.
这是你们的信函，
These are your packets,
你们会看到你们今天的任务是什么。
you will see what accounts you are  responsible for today.
我想你们会很快
I'm sure it hasn't taken you long to..
明白这次买卖的意义。
understand the implications of this sale.
对于你们和对手的关系，
还有你们的事业产生什么样的影响。
on your relationships with your counter-parties
and as a result...on your careers.
我对董事会说出了
I have expressed this
真相
reality
他们也很理解这一点。
to the executive committee and they understand.
所以，
As a result,
如果你能卖出你手里93%的资产，
if you achieve a 93% sale of your assets...
你会得到140万美元的奖金。
you will receive a 1.4 million dollar one off bonus.
如果这层楼整体
If the floor as a whole
销售完成了93%，你们每人会另外获得130万美元的奖励。
achieves a 93% sale you will
get an additional 1.3 million a piece.
如果你们没有经历过这样的事，
For those of you who have never been
through this before,
那么我告诉你这就是大甩卖的开始。
this is what the beginning of a fire sale looks like.
不用我告诉你头一个半小时有多么重要了。
I cannot begin to tell you
how important first hour and half is gonna be.
我要你们找到每一个可以找到的买家。
I want you to hit every bite you can find.
商人、经纪人、顾客……
Dealers, brokers, clients...
甚至如果你妈也想买的话。
Your mother, if she respond.
不要掉期交易，
No swaps.
我们今天只卖出。
It's outgoing only,
today.
显然这不是我们所希望看到的，
Obviously, this isn't going  down the way
that any of us would've hoped.
但是我们脚下的大地在颤抖了，
but the ground is shifting below our feet,
我们也没有别的选择。
And apparently,
there is no other way out.
上帝啊，现在真的面临一个很特殊的局面……
Gods... this is Obviously,
a very very unique situation...
如果我们今天成功了，
if we are successful today.
我们同时也会成功的砸了我们以后的饭碗。
We will have been successful in
destroying our own jobs...
我不能像你们保证所有人都……
I can not promise that any of you..
all of you...
你们当中有一些人还是会被公司解雇。
Some of you would be repositioned within the firm.
但我可以说，我为我们今天在这里的工作感到骄傲。
but I can tell you that, I am very proud
of the work we've done here today.
我在这家公司，
I have been at this place,
已经34年了，
34 years,
从我的经验来看，有人会对我们今天做的事情问候你们八辈儿祖宗。
I can tell you from experience, that people are going to say
some very nasty things about what we do here today.
同时也会这样问候你们所效力的公司。
about what you've dedicated a portion of your lives to.
但说实话，总体来说，
But have faith that in the bigger picture,
我们展现了我们的能力，
our skills have not been wasted,
我们获得了许多成就，
we have accomplished much,
我们的天赋，
and our talents
用以
have been used...
达成更伟大的事业。
for the greater good.
这是你们的信函，加油干吧。
Here's your packets,
get to work.
接线员：西铁事务所，我是埃里克。
- 让埃利奥特接电话。
Phone man: City..this is Eric.
- Give me Elliott.
- 西铁。
- 嘿，我是威尔・艾默生。
- City.
- Hey, its Will Emerson.
- 威廉啊，你怎么样？
- 我很好，最近干的怎么样？
- William, how are you?
- I'm alright, how's the trouble at scribes?
总是输的一塌糊涂。
Busting my ass, as always.
你看，我就说你应该相信我。
You see, that's what i've been trying to tell you.
John, why do you thing I'm saying this?
我知道。
I know you did.
你要我做什么？
What can i do for you?
我刚得到点儿消息，
Listen, I just got tapped on my shoulder,
我们有点项目要转移。
we've got some words over here
that we need to move.
所以今天我的亏损就是你的收益。
So, today. It looks like my lost is your gain.
多大的盘子？
What kind of size you're talking about?
应该在你的屏幕上，我发给你了。
Should be on your screen,
I just sent it.
- 天哪，什么价？
- 96美元一股。
- Jesus, what is this gonna land?
- 96 on a dollar.
- 91美元。
- 你都拿走，94美元。
- 91?
- Whole three and we're done at 94.
- 93.5美元？
- 成交！
- 93 and a half?
- Done!
- 交易所。
- 嗨美女～
- This is trading?
- Hello, gorgious.
- 威尔，你们那怎么了？
- 今天是转移交易日。
- Will, what's happening over there?
- Today's moving day.
- 你们他妈的要干什么？
- 他们什么都没说，我就知道这个
- What's the fuck are you guys so worked up about?
- You think they tell me anything, all i know is that
今天我的亏损就是你的收益。你对我们那么好，
today my loss is your gain.
Now, you're friendly
所以我就先找你来了。
So, I'm coming to you first.
I got two seventy mill
我这有2亿7千万的担保基金，20年付清还有15年。
a fifteen year paying at a twenty half a part.
- 从哪来的？
- 哪来的？谁在乎这个？
- Where is it from?
- Where is it from? Do you care?
不是吧……
No, not really. Now...
- 哪交易的？我听说你们……
- 我现在只告诉了你这个事。
- Where's the trade? I'm hearing that you guys....
- I'm only sharing this with you right now!
- 85美元。
- 好的。
- 85...
- Done.
我多维奇。
Deutsche?
我是威尔・艾默生。
Its Will Emerson.
- 操你妈，你这个骗子。
- 不是吧，你还为那事儿生气呢？
- Fuck you, you lying bastard.
- Come on, are you still angry about that.
这事儿都传出去了，我挂了。
Word is out, i'm hanging up.
- 我麦罗。
- 我劳伦斯。
- Merryll?
- Lawrence.
你们他妈的在干吗啊？
What the fuck are you guys doing over there?
- 就是一次春季扫货。
- 我听说可不是这样的。
- Just a little spring cleaning.
- That is not what i'm hearing.
- 好了劳伦斯，你是个买家吗？
- 不一定，什么东西？
- Alright, Lawrence. Are you a buyer?
- I'm not sure anymore. Where at?
怎么搞得，好像我要问你要卖什么货一样？
Why, it sounds like I should be asking 'Where at.'
75美分的三十年付清混合担保。
- 操……
- 375 mill at third year mix.
- Fuck me..
你要不要？
Are you with me on this?
- 63美分。
- 别蛋逼了，我挂了。
- 63 cents?
- or fuck you, I'm hanging up.
- 就63。
- 我问一下，5分钟后告诉你。
- 63?
- I'll come back to you on five.
或者65.5。
Maybe, sixty five and five.
稍等，别挂。
Well, alright then, stay on the line.
山姆，接电话。
Sam, pick up the phone.
山姆，接电话！
Sam...get on the line!
- 我刚联系了劳伦斯。
- 什么情况？
- I got Lawrence in now.
- Where are we?
- 63美分。
- 老天，买什么？
- sixty three cent.
- Jesus, and what?
给他65，卖了。
Get him to sixty five and hit it.
你他妈开什么玩笑？
Are you fucking kidding me on this?
那可是在一个交易上就损失了1亿美元。
That's a hundred million lost on a single trade.
我知道，卖了。
I understand...hit it.
好吧劳伦斯，65，靠谱儿么？
Well, Lawrence. We'd fill a kill at sixty five.
妥了。
It's filled.
干的不错。
Well done.
我想过来帮帮你，但他们现在就开始裁员了。
I just wanna give you heads up.
They're gonna start sending a few people home now.
- 现在？
- 对，而且没什么商量的。
- Now?
- Yes, I know this ends.
坐。
Please sit.
恭喜你把这事儿干的有条不紊。
Congratulations are clearly in order.
我们尽力了。
We did the best we could.
你确实做了不少事情。
You did a hell of a job.
我很感激，坐吧。
And i thank you for that.
C'mon sit.
不好意思我在吃东西，
Excuse me for eating, but...
今天真的很不容易。
It's been a long day.
- 你要点什么吗？
- 不用了，谢谢。
- Can i get you something?
- No, nothing, Thanks.
- 要我做什么？
- 我要辞职。
- What can i do for you?
- I want out.
- 我做完了，我要辞职。
- I'm done, I want out.
- 这一天很不容易……
- 我要你把我的期货全都放了，
- It's a very difficult day for all...
- I need you to release my options,
如果以后它们还值钱的话，我要我的分红，但是我要辞职。
If they're worth anything today,
I want my bonus, I am out.
你可以保留你的分红，你的期货……
You'll get your bonus,
your options...
但是蛋腚点儿。但我要你再干24个月。
and keep a calm face. But i need you to stay
with me for next 24 months..
你今天做的很好，你也这么觉得吧。
You did some good today,
you said that yourself.
知道吗
You know...
这之后我对整件事的感觉好多了。
I'm starting to feel
a little better about all this whole thing.
山姆，你是世界上最幸运的人。
You're one of the luckiest guy in the world, Sam.
如果不是做这个你还在挖战壕呢。
You could've been digging dicks
all this years.
那倒是。
That's true.
如果我那么做的话，至少
And if i had, at least...
我就不知道我们怎么把事搞得这么恶心？
How the hell did we fuck this up,
quite so much?
你什么时候开始觉得对不起大家了……真受不了你。
When did you start feeling so sorry
for yourself..its unbearable.
怎么，你觉得我们今天让一些人破产了。
So, you think we might've put a few
people out of business today.
这都是徒然。
It's all for note.
但你做这样的事情都快40年了。
But you've been doing that everyday,
for almost 40 years Sam
如果你觉得这是浮云，那所有的东西都是了。
If this is all for note, then so is everything out there.
这就是钱的事儿。
Its just money.
都是假的，虚构的。
It's made up.
纸上画着画，
It's pieces of paper with a picture on it.
So, we don't have to
所以我们就不用相互残杀，来点东西吃吧。
kill each other, just to get something to eat.
这没什么不对的。
Its not wrong.
现在和原来也没什么区别。
And it's certainly not different today,
then it's ever been.
1637, 1797, 1819, 1937，1957
1984,
1901, 1907
1929, 1937..1974
还有1987年，天啊！都差点整死我。
1987, Jesus!
Didn't that fucker fuck me up good.
1992、1997、2000年，不管怎么说。
92, 97..2000
and whatever we wanna call this.
都是同样的事情，周而复始的，我们改变不了什么。
All just for same thing,
over and over..we can't help ourselves.
我们会想要，嗯……
And we wanna like uh,
控制它、或者阻止它或者减缓它的发展。
可是我们从来都没能改变过什么。
Control it, or stop it or even slow it.
We haven't even since slightly altered.
我们只能应对。
We just react.
如果我们做对了，就能赚到很多钱。
We get a lot of money,
if we get it right.
而如果我们做错了，就被人们抛弃。
And we get left by the side of road,
if we get it wrong.
一直就是这样，以后也会一直这样，赢家和输家的比例是不变的。
And there has always been, and always will be..
the same percentage of winners and losers
快乐的小二逼和可怜的倒霉蛋。
happy fucks and sad sacks.
世界上就是肥猫和饿狗。
Fat cats and starving dogs, in this world.
现在世界上可能我们这样的人比之前多。
Yeah, then maybe more of us today,
than there ever been...
但是比例，
but the percentage,
和原来是一样的。
they stand exactly the same.
好吧我会继续干，但不是因为你的一分钟演说，
I'll do it John, not but because of the little speech,
而是因为我需要钱。
But because I need the money.
真不敢相信，这么多年了，我还是需要拼命挣钱。
Hard to believe, after all this years..
But I... need the money.
你要留着那小子吗？
Are you gonna keep the kid?
留着他？他会升职的。
Keep him? He's gonna promote him.
看戴克怎么处理了。
Its all hands on deck now Sam.
这事儿之后我们会有很多钱可挣，
There's gonna be a lot of money to be made,
coming out of this mess.
所以我们需要所有能找到的智囊团来帮我们。
And they're gonna need all the brains,
we can get out on here.
我从兽医那回来，我不知道能去哪儿。
I went home from the vet
and I couldn't think of where as to go.
她属于这。
She belongs here.
我知道，但山姆你已经不在这住了。
I know, but Sam you don't live here anymore.
你没事吧？你看起来不太好。
Are you alright?
You don't look so good.
没事，今天真是够背的。
Yeah, it's been a rough day all the way around.
我知道，萨米说了。
I know, Sammy called.
他还好么？
Is he alright?
他被裁了，
They got hammered,
但他还好。
but got out alive.
那就好。
Good.
好吧我先进屋睡了。
Well, I am going to go back inside and go back to bed.
有警报，所以别想闯进来。
The alarm is on so don't try to break in.
你自己保重。
Take care of yourself.
BYR 一代贱侠小春春 自行翻译